in the last video
在上一个视频中
we work through an example of using a computation graph
我们讲解了一个使用计算图的例子
to compute a function J
来计算代价函数J
now let's take a cleaned up version at their computation graph
现在让我们来看一个空的计算图
and show how you can use it
来演示你该怎样使用它
to figure out derivative calculations for that function J
以便于弄清楚代价函数J的求导运算
so here's a computation graph
这是一个计算图
let's say you want to compute
比方说 你想要计算
the derivative of J with respect to v
代价函数J对v的导数
so what is that   well
那么
this says if we were to take this value of v and change it a little bit
我的意思是说 如果我们把v的值改变一点点
how would the value of J change
代价函数J的值将会怎样变化
well J is defined as  3 times v
那么 J定义为3乘v
and right now v is equal to 11
现在v等于11
so then with the bump up v by a little bit
那么我们把v提高一点点
to 11.001 then J which is currently 33
达到11.001 那么现在值还是33的J
will end up being bumped up to 3 times
将会是现在v的三倍
a new value of v becomes 33.001 (33.003) and so
新值是33.001(Ng笔误 应是33.003)
if you bump up v by 0.001  um..
如果你给v增加0.001  呃
then J which is 3 v so currently 33
那么J等于3v,之前还是33
will get bumped up to 33.003
J就将会增加到33.003
so here we've increased v by 0.001
我们已经给v增加0.001
and the net result of that is
这个神经网络的结果是
that J goes up three times as much
J增加为三倍
so the derivative of J of respect to v is equal to three
所以J对v的导数为3
because the increase in J is three times the increase in v
因为J的增加为3倍就是由于v增加为原本3倍
and in fact
事实上
this is very analogous to the example we had in the
这和我们在之前视频中举的例子很相似
previous video where we had on f of a equals three a
在那个例子中我们f(a)=3a
and so we then derive that df da
那么接下来我们求df/da(f对a的导数)
which was slightly simplified
，让我们简化一下,
letting sloppy notation you can read it
比如写成你能容易理解的标记，
df da was equal to three
就是df/da=3
right   so instead here we have  J equals 3v
那么  我们这里有J=3v
and so dj dv is equal to three
和dj/dv =3
with here J playing the role of f
这里的J起着上个例子中函数f的作用
and v playing the role of a in this previous example
v起着上个例子中的a的作用
that we had right from  an earlier video
右边这些标记来自于早先的视频
so indeed
事实上
terminology of backpropagation what
反向传播这个术语
we're seeing is that if you want to compute
我们现在看到的就是你是否想要计算
the derivative of this final output variable
最终输出变量的导数
which usually is a variable  you care most about
那通常是一个你最关心的变量
with respect to v
至于v
then we've done you know sort of one step of  backpropagation
我们已经做了你有所了解的一个步骤 反向传播
so we've gone one step backwards in this graph
我们在这张图中已经进行了一步反向
now let's look at another example
现在让我们看下另一个例子
what is dj da
dj/da是什么
in other words if we bump up the value of a
换句话说 如果我们增大a的值
how does that affect the value of J
那么J的值会受到什么样的影响
well let's go through the example right now
让我们现在仔细看下这个例子
a is equal to five so let's bump it up to 5.001
a等于5 让我们把它增大到5.001
the net impact of that is at v
另外最终受影响是v
which was a plus u so that was previous 11 that
它是a加u 所以之前的值11
we can increase to 11.001
我们可以增加到11.001
and then we've already seen as above
现在我们在上面已经看到
that J now gets bump up to 33.003
J现在的值是33.003
so what we've seen is that
现在我们已经看到
if you increase a by 0.001
如果你把a增加了0.001
J increases by 0.003
J增加了0.003
and by increase a I mean maybe
通过增大a的值 我的意思是说
you were to take this value five and just plug in a new value
你可以尝试拿这个值5 然后加上一个新的值
right then the change to a
然后a的变化
will propagate to the right of the computation graph
将会被传递到计算图的右边
so the J ends up being 33.003
结果J变成了33.003
and so the increase the J is three times the increase the a
所以J增加的值是a增加值的3倍
so that means this derivative is equal to three
所以这意味着这里导数是3
and one way to break this down
一种具体解析它原理的办法
is to say that if you have
是说如果
if you change a
你改变a
then that will change v and through changing v that
那么v就会被改变 通过改变v
will change J and
就会改变J
so the net change to the value of J when you bump up the value
所以当你增加值的时候 J的净值改变
and when you nudge the value of a up a little  bit
当将a的值提高一点的时候
is that    first by changing a
（J的净值改变）首先是通过改变a
you end up increasing v
结果改变了v
well  how much does v increase right
这样 v恰好增加多少
it is increased by an amount determined by dv da
是由dv/da的大小决定的
and then the change in v will cause
然后v的变化将导致
the value of J to also increase
J的值同样增加
so in calculus is actually called the chain rule
这个运算在微积分中事实上叫做链式法则
that is a affects v , affects J then the
就是a影响v,影响J
amount that J changes where you nudge a
当增大a时，J的改变值等于
is the product of how much v changes
基于v改变的一个乘积
when you nudge a     times how much J changes when you nudge v
这就是当你改变v时对应a的改变 乘以 J的改变
so in calculus
在微积分中
the gate is called the chain rule and
这个被叫做链式法则
what we saw from this calculation is
我们从这个计算中看到
that if you increase a 0.001
如果你增加a 0.001
v changes by the same amount so dv da is equal to one
v就改变相同的量因为这时dv/da是1
so in fact if you plug in
所以事实上如果你插入
what we have worked out previously on
我们之前算出的
dv dJ is equal to three and dv da is equal to one
dj/dv 等于3  并且dv/da=1
so the product of these
所以他们的积是
three times one
3乘以1
then I should give you the correct value that dj da is equal to 3
现在我告诉你   dj/da的正确的值是3
so this illustration shows how
这个解释展示了如何
by having computed dj dv
通过计算dj/dv
of this derivative respect to this variable
来求这个变量的导数
it can then help you to compute dj da and
它可以帮助你计算dj/da
so that's another step within some backward calculation
这是反向运算中的另一步
I'll just introduce one more
我将会介绍另外一种
new notational convention
新的符号惯例
which is that in when you're writing code to implement
当你编写代码实现
back-propagation they'll usually be some
反向传播的时候 它们通常作为一些
final output variable that you really care about
你所在意的最终的输出变量
right   so the final output variable that you really care about
即你所在意的最终输出变量
whether you want to optimize
无论你是否想要优化
and in this case
在这种情况下
this final output variable is J
最终的输出变量J
is really the last node in your computation graph
确实是你的计算图中的最后一个节点
and so a lot of the computations will
并且因此许多运算将会
be trying to compute
被尝试计算
the derivative of that you know final output variable
最终输出变量的导数
so d of this final output variable
即这个 FinalOutputVar变量
with respect to some other variable
对其它的变量
and just call that d var
或者称作dvar的变量的导数
right
so a lot of the computations
有很多计算
you have would be to compute the derivative of the final output variable
你可能需要计算最终输出变量的导数
really J in this case
在这个例子中是J
with various intermediate variables
有着很多中间变量
such as a b c  u or v and when
比如a b c u 和 v
you implement this in software
你在软件中实现它们
you know what you call this variable name alright
你知道这个变量的变量名叫什么
one thing you could do is in in python
你在python中可以做的一件事是
you can write you give it a
你可以给他一个
very long variable name as dfinaloutputvar over  dvar
非常长的变量名作为 dFinaleOutputVar 除以dvar
but that's a very long variable name
但是这个非常长的变量名
you could call these
你也可以称作
dJ dvar  but because
dJ dvar  但是因为
you're always taking derivatives respect to dJ
你总是要对dJ求导
respect to this final output variable
对于这个最终的输出变量
I'm going to introduce a new notation  we're in code
我会介绍一些我们在代码中用到的新的符号
when you are computing this thing in the code you write
当你在你在代码中计算这个东西的时候
we're just going to use the variable name dvar in order to represent that quantity
我们就简单地使用变量名dvar来表示数量
okay so
那么
dvar in the code you write
你代码中写的dvar
will represent the derivative of the final output variables you care  about
将表示你所关心的最终输出变量的导数
such as J
比如说J
or sometimes the loss L with respect
或者是损失函数 L
to the various intermediate quantities in computing in your code
计算过程对应的你代码中的中间值
so this thing
所以
here in your codes you know you use the dv
你代码中这里你使用 dv
to denote this value
来标记它的值
so dv would be equal to 3
那么 dv将会等于3
and your code you represent as da
在你的代码中表示da
right which is    we also figured out to be equal to 3
我们得到的结果是3
okay so  with the backpropagation
由于反向传播
partially through this computation graph
部分经过这个计算图
let's go through the rest of this example  on the next slide
让我们看下这个例子在另一侧剩下的部分
so let's go to
那么 让我们换个
a cleaned up copy of the computation graph
一个这个计算图干净的版本
and just to recap what we've done
然后回忆我们已经完成的部分
so far is go backward here and
到现在是反向进行运算
figured out that dv is equal to 3
发现了dv等于3
and again the definition of dv that's just the
再复述一遍 这里的dv仅仅是
variable name of the code
代码里面的变量名
is really dj dv
表示真正的dj/dv
I will figured out that da is equal to 3
我们将看到 da=3
and again da is the variable name in your code
再重复一遍 da在这里只是你的代买里面的变量的名字
and that's really the value of dj da
它是dj/da的真正的值
and what sort of hand wave how   you know
那么在这里
we've gone backwards  on these two edges like so
我们怎样对两边进行反向传播的呢
now let's keep computing derivatives
现在让我们计算导数
or let's look at the value u
或者说 让我们看下这个值u
so what is dJ du   well
那么dj/du是什么呢
through a similar calculation is what we did before
通过一次类似之前做过的运算
and we start off with u equals 6
我们从u=6开始
if you bump up u to the 6.001
如果你将u增加到6.001
then v which is previous 11 goes up to 11.001
然后之前是11的v就增加到11.001
and so J goes from 33 to 33.003
J就从33增加到了33.003
and so the increase in J is 3 X
所以J是增加了3倍v所增加的值
so this is equal
这是等价的
and the analysis that u is very similar to the analysis we did for a
关于u的分析和我们之前对a做的分析非常相似
this is actually computed
其实计算的是
as a dj dv times dv du
dj/dv乘上dv/du
where this we had already figured out was 3
我们已经得出结果是3
and this turns out to be equal to 1
现在这次运算结果是1
so we've kind of one more step backpropagation
那么 我们多了一步反向传播
we end up computing that du is also equal to 3
我们得出结果是du也等于3
and du is of course just as dj du now
现在du当然也是和dj/du的值一样
we just step through one last example in detail
现在我们详细看下最后一个例子
so what is dj db   right
那么 dJ/db 又是什么呢
so you imagine if you are allowed to change the value of b
想象一下如果你被允许改变的值
and you want to tweak b a little bit
你想要调整一点b的值
in order to minimize or
来最小化
maximize the value of J  right
或者最大化J的值
so what is the derivative
那么导数是什么
what's the slope of this function J
函数J的梯度是什么
when you change the value of b a little bit
在你改变b的值一点点的时候
it turns out that using the chain rule for calculus
结果是使用链式法则来计算
this can be written as
这个可以写作
the product of two things is dj du times du db and
dJ/du与du/db的积
the reasoning is if you change b a little bit
理由是如果你改变了b一点点
so b goes from 3 to say 3.001
比如b从3增加到3.001
the way of the affect J
这样对J的影响是
is it will first affect u
它会首先影响u
so how much does it affect u   well
那么 它对u产生了多大的影响
u is defined as b times c right
u是b乘以c的积
so this will go from six when b is equal to 3  to now  6.002
那么当b等于3的时候 u从6到增加到现在的6.002
right because c is equal to 2 in our example  here
在我们现在这个例子中因为c等于2
and so this tells us that
这就告诉了我们du/db的值
du db is equal to 2
du/db也等于2
because when you pump up b by 0.001
因为当你给b增加0.001的时候
you increase this twice as much
你给u增加为原来的两倍
so du db this is equal to 2
所以du/db等于2
and now we know that u has gone up twice as much as b has gone up
现在我们知道当b增加为2倍的时候 u也是这样增加
well once dj du you we've already figured out
我们之前已经发现dj/du
that this is equal to 3
是等于3的
and so by multiplying these two out
所以通过把它们两个乘起来
we find that dj db is equal to 6
我们发现dj/db等于6
and again here's the reasoning for the second part of the argument
我们为什么再次思考这个参数的第二部分
which is we want to know
因为我们想要知道
when you goes up by 0.002
当你把b提高了0.002的时候
how does that affect J the fact that
J受到了什么影响 事实上
dj du is equal to 3 that tells us that
dJ/du等于3 这告诉了我们
when you goes up by 0.002
当你把b提高0.002
J goes up three times as much
J则提高这个数值的3倍
so J should go up by 0.006 right
所以J应当提高0.006
that's comes from in fact that dj du is equal to three
事实上这是因为dj/du等于3
and if you check the map in detail
如果你仔细检查了这张图
you will find that if b becomes 3.001
你会发现如果b变为3.001
then u become 6.002
那么u的值成了6.002
v becomes 11.002  all right
v变成了11.002
so that's a plus u so this 5 Plus u and
所以a 加 u 就是 5加 u
then J which is equal to 3 times v then
那么J等于3乘以v
ends up being equal to 33.006  right
结果成了33.006
and so that's how you get that dj db is equal to 6
所以你计算dj/db得到的值是6
and to fill that in
并把这个填充进来
this is if we go backwards
如果我们反向传播
so this is db is equal to 6 and db really is
那么db就等于6  这里db指的是
the Python code variable name
python代码里面的变量名
for you know dj db
你所知晓的那个真正的dj db
and  I won't go through the last example in great detail
我并不打算仔细过一遍最后这个例子
but it turns out that if you also computes out dj da
但是事实证明 如果你计算dJ/da
this turns out to be dj du times du da and
答案就是dj/du乘上du/da
this turns out to be 9
这个式子中的结果是9
it turns out to be three times three
就是3乘以3
I won't go through that example in detail
这一点我不会再详细讲述
but through this last step
但是通过这最后一步
you know it is possible to derive that dc is equal to
你可以看到这是可以导出dc的值的
so the key take away from this video
所以视频中这个例子的关键是
from this example is that when computing
当计算
derivatives in computing all of these derivatives
导数的时候   通过计算所有这些导数
the most efficient way to do so
最有效的办法是
is through a right-to-left computation
通过从右至左计算
following the direction of the event arrows
按照这个箭头事件所指的方向
and in particular
尤其是
we'll first compute the derivative respect to v
我们先计算对v的导数
and then that
然后
becomes useful for computing the derivative respect to a
计算对a的导数变得很有用了
and the derivative with respect to u and
对u的导数也是这样
then the derivative respect to u   for example
然后对u的导数  举个例子
this term for example this term over here
这个式子 还有这里这个式子
and this term over here
还有这里这个式子
those in turn become useful for computing
这些结果都变得对于计算它们
their derivative of respact to b
对b的偏导数很有用 和
and in the derivative of respect to c
对c的偏导数很有用
so those computation driven
所以这些计算驱动
how there's a forward or left to right calculation
前向或者说从左至右计算
to compute the cost function such as J
来算出代价函数如J
you might want to optimize and a backward
你或许想要选择一个反向
or a right to left calculation to
或者说从右至左的运算来
derivatives   if you're not familiar with
计算导数    这是在你不熟悉
compute calculus or the chain rule
计算微积分 或者说链式法则时候所做的
I know some of those details would have gone by really quickly
我知道这些细节可能过的有些快
but you didn't follow all the details
但是你不必太过关注这里的细节
don't worry about it
不必担心这个
in the next video we'll go for this again
在下一个视频中  我们还会再次做这个
in the context of logistic regression and
在逻辑回归的上下文并
show you exactly what you need to do
教给你需要学什么
in order to implement the computations
来实现这个计算
you need to compute the derivatives of the logistic regression model
你需要计算逻辑回归模型中的导数